Curriculum vitae

Personal Information

FIRST NAME / SURNAME Betty Tsotetsi
PHONE NUMBER 079 975 9504

EMAIL betty58tso@gmail.com
ADDRESS Ferndale, South Africa

LANGUAGES English, Sotho, Zulu, Tswana, Xhosa, Pedi

SUMMARY: I am detail oriented, team spirited, highly disciplined - currently working for eNCA as a Video Wall Graphics Operator. Worked as an On Air Graphics operator in the same company. An in-house graphic artist for a corporate branding company and an in-house graphic designer for a communications company prior to that. Among other skills, all these roles requires one to be highly computer literate and have in one way or the other required one to have the ability to listen attentively, multi task and also be able to work with different people and personalities. A firm believer in giving everything I do the best of me.

Experience

COMPANY eNCA

POSITION Video Wall Operator

DURATION 2019 to date

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Communicating with the team(PA, Graphics operator, Technical director, assistant production editor, server operator) to ensure that we're all working on the same piece at the same time.
- Communicating with vision control to ensure the shots can accommodate the story plasmas and vision mixer to assist when I'm still busy with shots
- Selecting images/videos for stories in the rundown
- Trouble shooting
- Checking and playing out graphics on air
- Ensuring that graphics are working correctly
- Editing images and videos to match the package/

story being played out

COMPANY eNCA

POSITION On Air graphics Operator(2014 - 2019) **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Taking instructions from technical director and executing as required

- Working within a team to put a flawless product on air while completing individual tasks

- Trouble shooting whenever the situation requires

- Checking and playing out graphics on air

- Making sure graphics are operating correctly

- Ensuring I have correct names(correctly spelled and accompanied by correct titles) for guests

COMPANY Oranges Promo

POSITION In-house graphic artist (August 2011 - June 2014)

- Preparing and sending out quotes to clients

- Liaising with clients and production team to create final artworks and ensuring everything is approved

before final print

- Communicating with the printing team to ensure

that they are aware of the set deadline

- Drawing up a schedule on what's urgent and

what can be pushed back

- Following up on process with the decorators and

giving feedback to customers

COMPANY Zazise Communications

POSITION In-house Graphic Designer(February 2011 - June

2011(2 Months Contract Extended))

RESPONSIBILITIES:

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Working with both the sales and PR teams to

design promotional items

- Putting together PowerPoint presentations for

both the sales and PR representatives

- Creating a newspaper layout for a local

newspaper

- Designing promotional materials for both in-

house and company's clients

EDUCATION

National diploma | Graphic Design | February 2008 - November 2010 Tlhorong senior secondary school | Grade 12 (National senior certificate) | 2005

References available upon request